Howard Jess

Web Application UI/UX Developer

<u>hjess@mail.com</u> <u>linkedin.com/in/hjess</u> <u>206.412.9924</u>

Brief

I thrive and excel in a collaborative team environment; after many experiences in desktop applications, system programming, and networking infrastructure, I settled into web application UI development as an interesting intersection of them all. I'm especially interested in user experience, elegant design, and accessibility.

Skills

Tools: Bourne shell, GIMP, Git, VIM

Languages: <u>Javascript, Typescript, HTML, CSS (Less, SASS/SCSS), TCL, C</u>

Systems: Linux, Unix, Mac OS/X, Windows

UI Technologies: Bootstrap, Element UI, DOM, HTTP, i18n/I10n, jQuery, Knockout, MVC, REST, TCP/IP, Vue.js

Development: Agile, Scrum, Kanban

Experience

Trupanion

Front-end Web Application Developer

April 2017 \rightarrow June 2023

Javascript, Typescript, Vue, SCSS, CSS, Bootstrap, HTML, Razor (C# templates), SignalR, ASP.Net, Git

Brought in as Trupanion's first UI specialist. Projects:

- <u>Member Portal</u> (lead UI dev): led UI team, writing a .NET-MVC/SPA hybrid from scratch, providing customers access to their account. *VanillaJS. Typescript, iQuery, Vue, Sass*
- Website 3.0 (UI team member): part of a rewrite team for the main public-facing website. VanillaJS, jQuery, Sass, Sitecore
- <u>VetPortal</u> (lead UI dev): led a full rewrite of Trupanion's veterinary hospital software (.NET-MVC/SPA hybrid), from VanillaJS/jQuery/KnockoutJS/Kendo to Vue/Bootstrap, reducing network payload by 50%. *Vue, SignalR, Razor*
- Hospital Management Tool (sole UI dev): created an application (SPA) providing internal support for VetPortal.
 Vue, Element
- Partner Portal (sole UI dev): created an application (SPA) allowing State Farm agents to create & manage their portfolio of Trupanion policies. Vue
- Agent Reassignment Tool (sole UI dev): created an application (SPA) allowing State Farm managers to manage policy re-distribution among agents. Vue

Navigating Cancer (contract position)

Front-end Web Application Developer

June 2016 → February 2017

Bootstrap, Coffeescript, Backbone.js, HAML, JSON Schema, JSON Editor, Mocha, Ruby on Rails, SASS

Developer for Navigating Cancer's suite of Patient Care Management software, dedicated to improving and streamlining the relationship and care experience for cancer patients and oncology clinics. Projects:

- Complex Triage Pathways: implemented a set of <u>JSON Schema+JSON Editor</u>-based dynamic forms to standardize symptom data recording for cancer patients
- · Living Style Guide: continued work to maintain and upgrade the development group's style and component library

Howard Jess

Web Application UI/UX Developer

hjess@mail.com linkedin.com/in/hjess 206.412.9924

Rosetta Stone (acquired Livemocha in April 2013)

Front-end Web Application Developer

November 2012 → April 2016

AngularJS, CouchDB, HTML, Javascript, Mixpanel, SCSS, Sproutcore

Developer for Rosetta Stone's <u>Advanced English for Business</u> language-learning application, and <u>Livemocha</u>, a social community-based language-learning application. Projects:

- · Password reset/recovery
- · User profile management
- · Partner connections
- Analytics, using Mixpanel Analytics
- Full language-learning engine (a <u>SPA</u>) rewrite from <u>Sproutcore</u> to <u>AngularJS</u>.

Optify, Inc.

Front-end Software Engineer

September 2011 → October 2012

Backbone.js, HTML, Javascript, LESS, Mixpanel

UI developer for Optify's *Inbound Marketing* software suite, a <u>SAAS</u> tool for B2B marketers. Projects:

- · Customer site "Landing Page" editor/publisher
- · Contact Manager & Email Manager tools
- Analytics, using Mixpanel Analytics
- · Rewrote UI coding standards document, and overhauled the Javascript library namespace

Cobalt.com, Inc.

Senior UI Developer

September 2009 → September 2011

Lead UI developer on Cobalt's *New Products* team, charged with creating and delivering innovative website products for sale to auto manufacturers and dealers. Projects:

- Embedded Google maps for location pages
- Facebook and Twitter publishing and feed widgets
- Embedded YouTube player/playlist handler
- Initial implementation of front-end unit testing using jstestdriver

Education

Northwestern University

B.A., Economics